<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infrastructure as Code on Azure Freak Confessions</title><link>/tags/infrastructure-as-code/</link><description>Recent content in Infrastructure as Code on Azure Freak Confessions</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/infrastructure-as-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure IPAM Pools - WORK IN PROGRESS!</title><link>/post/azure-ipam-pools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/azure-ipam-pools/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ipam-pools----azure-virtual-network-manager">IPAM Pools - Azure Virtual Network Manager&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Have you ever had to manage your IP-Addresses within Azure and make sure there are not overlapping ranges. Or had to find out which IP-Address range was still available.
For me this was such a tedious task, especialy working in a team and potentially forgetting to update wiki pages, Excel files or other documents scattered across various systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terraform</title><link>/glossary/terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Terraform is an infrastructure as code tool that lets you build, change, and version cloud and on-prem resources safely and efficiently.
It deploys infrastructure using providers, there are different providers available from HashiCorp (the owner of Terraform) and from the community.
For that reason it is a widely known and used language to deploy infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Managed DevOps Pools</title><link>/post/managed-devops-pools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/managed-devops-pools/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="managed-devops-pools">Managed DevOps Pools&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Have you ever had to deploy, configure, and maintain your own DevOps agents, be it for Azure DevOps or GitHub? If so, then you probably found out it is such a hassle to keep everything up-to-date and up-and-running.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infrastructure as Code</title><link>/glossary/infrastructure-as-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/infrastructure-as-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is a DevOps methodology that allows you to manage your infrastructure as code. This means that you can use the same tools and processes as you use for your application code.
This allows you to automate the deployment of your infrastructure and to manage it in the same way as your application code. This is a very powerful concept that allows you to manage your infrastructure in a very efficient way.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>